<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>DaFoster</title>
 <link href="http://dafoster.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://dafoster.net"/>
 <updated>2013-01-25T04:07:57-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://dafoster.net</id>
 <author>
   <name>David Foster</name>
   
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Things I Wish I Knew Before Working in Industry</title>
   <link href="http://dafoster.net/articles/2013/01/15/things-i-wish-i-knew-before-working-in-industry/"/>
   <updated>2013-01-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://dafoster.net/articles/2013/01/15/things-i-wish-i-knew-before-working-in-industry</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In April 2008, a representative from IBM gave a presentation at Georgia
Tech about things he wished he knew before working in the the software
industry. I have found his advise to be very useful at various points during
my career. Sadly I have lost the presenter&amp;rsquo;s name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my outline of his presentation. &lt;strong&gt;Emphasized&lt;/strong&gt; points are ones I&amp;rsquo;ve found
to be particularly useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Technology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future: integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needed: ease-of-use &amp;amp; less complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; reinvent wheels!

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you&amp;rsquo;ll never finish the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Technical Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t need to take a class to learn something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn a little about a lot of things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read news highlights from worthwhile sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Problem Solving&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build a network of people. Asking for advice is quicker than learning the hard way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is always more than one way to do something.&lt;br/&gt;
Weigh the pros/cons of each – then pick and choose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovate &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; you execute. Think critically before you act.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Business &amp;amp; Technology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology adoption is driven by &lt;em&gt;business&lt;/em&gt;. (practicality)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business is nothing without technology.&lt;br/&gt;
Technology is nothing without business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you build a better mousetrap, they will not come.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A project, no matter how advanced, is doomed for failure without a paying customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about TCO (&lt;em&gt;total&lt;/em&gt; cost of ownership) and ROI (return on investment).&lt;br/&gt;
You must always justify your returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication with &lt;em&gt;managers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;customers&lt;/em&gt; is vital!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
If you can&amp;rsquo;t get someone to adopt your solution, what&amp;rsquo;s the point?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a difference between removing barriers and creating incentive (for a customer to switch to my project/product). You need both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Promotions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you know.&lt;br/&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; you know.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; knows &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you know.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing more of the same is not enough.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need to try new things – take on more responsibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing what is asked is not enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask you manager what the expectations are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Working with Others&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit + gratitude are not limited resources.&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say thank you!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give credit where due.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be ambitious but be humble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t make assumptions about others.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give people the benefit of the doubt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your lack of planning does not mean I need to treat your request as urgent.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do what you say you will. Keep your word.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reliable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dependable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best humor is &lt;em&gt;self-deprecating&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is always someone faster, smarter, and better looking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Managers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They don&amp;rsquo;t have a magic wand. They don&amp;rsquo;t automatically fix problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managers do not have a superset of the employees' (team members') knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managers can&amp;rsquo;t read minds. Don&amp;rsquo;t assume. Communicate explicitly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are responsible for your own career. But ask for help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;You and Your Job&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your job is what you make of it. Don&amp;rsquo;t be confined by a job description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work/Life balance doesn&amp;rsquo;t have good default settings. You must do &lt;em&gt;explicit&lt;/em&gt; actions.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;schedule for success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are not your job. Do not define yourself like this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Workers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re employed to &lt;em&gt;add value&lt;/em&gt;, not spend money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to stay busy, but are you accomplishing anything &lt;em&gt;worthwhile&lt;/em&gt;?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t needlessly clutter your schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t looking at it from a &lt;em&gt;customer perspective&lt;/em&gt;, you aren&amp;rsquo;t looking at it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t do everything. Pick what you &lt;em&gt;won&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; do.&lt;/strong&gt; (The world won&amp;rsquo;t end.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Employment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t expect your first job to be your dream job. Look for a &lt;em&gt;path&lt;/em&gt;, not an &lt;em&gt;endpoint&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be willing to stretch your comfort zone.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;geographically, work type, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll stagnate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know your employer&amp;rsquo;s business model.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HP = selling ink;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft = selling Office and Windows;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple = iPod and (to some extent) Macs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look at the annual reports for your company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get &lt;em&gt;internships&lt;/em&gt;, even if with competitors, maybe even delaying graduation.&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increases employment opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start looking and prepare much earlier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Successful Employment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to make a difference, look for chaos.&lt;br/&gt;
Stable environments offer little opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good employees &lt;em&gt;deal&lt;/em&gt; with challenges instead of pouting. &lt;em&gt;Adapt&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay above the commodity line (with regard to skill set and type of work done).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Life&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand other people&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;motivations&lt;/em&gt;.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makes it easier to find new ways of solving the underlying goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define your values and goals.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ex: What type of job do you want?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your &lt;em&gt;behaviors&lt;/em&gt; should support your goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expect your goals to change. Success is dynamic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let &lt;em&gt;others&lt;/em&gt; define success for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can get rich by getting more or &lt;em&gt;wanting less&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life is one great balancing act.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no single right way of doing things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balancing your priorities and goals is important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Programming is Fun. But What Matters is Solving a Real Problem.</title>
   <link href="http://dafoster.net/articles/2013/01/08/programming-is-fun-but-what-matters-is-solving-a-real-problem/"/>
   <updated>2013-01-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://dafoster.net/articles/2013/01/08/programming-is-fun-but-what-matters-is-solving-a-real-problem</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love programming. It tickles me when I stumble across a new programming language that lets me express concepts in a more clear and direct fashion. I love the cleanness and order than results after a good round of refactoring&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I enjoy the challenge of hacking away at a fiddly problem and testing all the cases to get a correct and bulletproof solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I have realized programming is merely an activity. It is a &lt;em&gt;means&lt;/em&gt;, not an &lt;em&gt;end&lt;/em&gt;. My work is not inherently valuable because I have created a piece of software. Rather it is because I have created software &lt;em&gt;that solves somebody&amp;rsquo;s problem&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore it is the &lt;em&gt;problem&lt;/em&gt; that deserves the most attention if you want to make a difference that people care about. In that vein I have been learning about the precepts of Customer Development and Customer Discovery, which deals with how to efficiently interact with customers to discover a problem that they care about.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct customer interaction, such as through in-person interviews of the general public, is way outside my comfort zone. However I will perservere. I think it is a very important skill for actually making a dent in the universe.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Refactoring&lt;/em&gt; is a systematic method for code cleanup: improving the structure of existing code without changing its behavior. I highly recommend the book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Refactoring-Improving-Design-Existing-Code/dp/0201485672&quot;&gt;Refactoring&lt;/a&gt; if you want a deep-dive into the topic.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- Speculation: --&gt; Business majors &amp;amp; managers recognize early on the importance of solving business problems. After all, their training is around organizing other people to solve problems they identify. (Although I feel they often focus overly on managing and not enough on problem identification.)&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a great practical workboard around Customer Discovery (which is the first quarter of Customer Development), I highly recommend Ash Maurya&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Running-Lean-Iterate-Works-OReilly/dp/1449305172&quot;&gt;Running Lean&lt;/a&gt;. For a full overview of Customer Development, I recommend Steve Blank&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Four-Steps-Epiphany-Successful-Strategies/dp/0976470705&quot;&gt;The Four Steps to the Epiphany&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs famously said he wanted to &amp;ldquo;put a dent in the universe&amp;rdquo;. And boy did he ever.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>This website is now powered by Jekyll</title>
   <link href="http://dafoster.net/articles/2012/12/21/this-website-is-now-powered-by-jekyll/"/>
   <updated>2012-12-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://dafoster.net/articles/2012/12/21/this-website-is-now-powered-by-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;And this is my first post using the new system. Articles are a lot easier to
write, so I will be posting more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously this site was powered by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://drupal.org&quot;&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt; engine. I found it overly
complex to maintain, especially for a single-user blog and portfolio website.
For more details see my post &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/2012/12/16/why-i-no-longer-use-drupal/&quot;&gt;Why I no longer use Drupal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why I no longer use Drupal</title>
   <link href="http://dafoster.net/articles/2012/12/16/why-i-no-longer-use-drupal/"/>
   <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://dafoster.net/articles/2012/12/16/why-i-no-longer-use-drupal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;b&gt;TLDR:&lt;/b&gt; Drupal is overly complex for a personal blog. It is hard to maintain. Simple static site generators are easier to work with in the long term.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My portfolio website was written during college using hand-coded HTML and used server-side includes to bring in common navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in January 2010 I remade my site in Drupal. It gained lots of fancy features such as first-class support for project categories and project languages. You could subscribe to almost any page as a feed. There were project specific updates that could be commented on. From a feature point of view, it rocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But some problems became apparent over time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security updates were frequent and difficult to apply correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t like writing articles on the site because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t use simple markup formats such as Markdown.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drupal has no good editor plugins for markup languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And its visual HTML editor generates messy HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theme I used for the site was complex and hard to modify.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the CSS often interfered with my article markup, necessitating me to drop into HTML when editing certain articles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was no sane way to test structural changes to the site locally and then automatically deploy them to production.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Normally this would be done by keeping the site structure in the filesystem and all user content in a database. This allows the filesystem contents to be easily deployed using &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt;, or similar techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drupal, by contrast, keeps its site structure in both the filesystem &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; in the database, along with user-generated content. Updating only the parts of the database related to site structure is cumbersome and error-prone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thus, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really change the site structure after my initial deployment to production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing was in revision control, which made me nervous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to hack the Drupal core to get my contact form to work with my web hosting provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the features of the site weren&amp;rsquo;t being used by readers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So now I am rewriting my site yet again in straight HTML (via a simple static site generator) and outsourcing all user generated content (like comments) to third party service providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple simple simple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic security. The web server just serves static files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic scalability, for the same reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple authoring in Markdown with powerful client-side text editors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant deployment with &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything in revision control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can use any web hosting provider. Hell, I can just use &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; for free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultimate control over the site theme and CSS. I can fix problems myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Retrospect vs. Time Machine</title>
   <link href="http://dafoster.net/articles/2010/11/13/retrospect-vs-time-machine/"/>
   <updated>2010-11-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://dafoster.net/articles/2010/11/13/retrospect-vs-time-machine</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The old Retrospect 6.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past I have used Retrospect 6.0 to backup my Macs, since it was one of
the few programs that reliably backed up everything correctly, with all the
metadata intact. But it is looking much less attractive these days&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It no longer finds my laptop on the network reliably, due to some bug.
Especially when switching between wireless and wired networks.
Thus I often miss backups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is slow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It does not groom backups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It stores everything inside a single monolithic file,
which is at risk of corruption.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;The new Retrospect 8.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest version of Retropect (8.0) is somewhat better but has some problems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It does not seem to backup all attributes correctly.
For example, volume icons do not seem to be restored correctly.
Inaccurate backups are useless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is more complicated to use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automatic grooming, although supported, is so slow to be practically unusable.
It takes maybe 2x as long to do one grooming operation as an incremental backup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Time Machine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there is Time Machine. Since my primary systems are 10.5+, I can use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; support reliable backup of all filesystem attributes,
since it was made by Apple, who is in a position to know about them.
Also, Apple typically makes solid products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has quick, automatic, incremental backups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also grooms automatically while it is backing up. Grooming behavior is
intelligent, keeping snapshots at sensible intervals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The single-file restore interface is precise, intuitive, and fast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Only wrinkle is that Time Machine is not really designed to backup to network
drives, however there are &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.stephenmorley.org/articles/time-machine-on-a-network-drive/&quot;&gt;instructions for circumventing this&lt;/a&gt;.
(Of course there is Time Machine + Time Capsule for network backups, but a
Capsule is egregiously expensive.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2012 Update&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time Machine misses a few filesystem attributes that Retrospect 6.0 nailed back
in the day, like volume icons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it may also strip HFS+ extended attributes, since applications appear
to be quarantined after they are restored from a Time Machine backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last nitpick is that TM has very poor handling for bad media and bad blocks.
In particular if your primary hard drive develops bad blocks, which is an early
sign of imminent failure, Time Machine will choke and refuse to backup the
entire volume. And this is exactly at the time you need it your files backed up
the most, when your hard drive is likely to fail.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Impact of Anime on my Programming Experience</title>
   <link href="http://dafoster.net/articles/2010/09/18/impact-anime-my-programming-experience/"/>
   <updated>2010-09-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://dafoster.net/articles/2010/09/18/impact-anime-my-programming-experience</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It occurs to me that anime has been an important driver for improving my programming abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did my own &lt;a href=&quot;/prism/projects/kiss/&quot;&gt;implementation of the Kisekae Set System&lt;/a&gt; (KiSS),
a digital paper doll system which often featured anime characters.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My very first exposure to anime was to the characters of Wedding Peach,
via an included doll file with the French KiSS viewer by John Stiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taught me how to write directly to graphics buffers, in both C and
later Java.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I initially picked up Java when I was writing &lt;strong&gt;RealMediaFixer&lt;/strong&gt;,
a repairer of RealMedia video files. CodeWarrior&amp;rsquo;s implementation of the
C++ iostream classes had a broken buffered stream implementation,
so I switched to Java to use its rock solid BufferedOutputStream
implementation.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial use was to repair &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.themanime.org/viewreview.php?id=396&quot;&gt;Ranma&lt;/a&gt; episodes that I downloaded over HTTP,
on dialup!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I implemented &lt;a href=&quot;/prism/projects/hotline/&quot;&gt;my own client and server for the Hotline protocol&lt;/a&gt;,
through which I got most of my anime prior to the introduction of
BitTorrent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today I am &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/handbrake-subtitle-support/&quot;&gt;enhancing support for transcoding soft subtitles in HandBrake&lt;/a&gt;
so that I can watch new anime on the bus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Comparing Writing Utensils (Why Pens&nbsp;>&nbsp;Pencils)</title>
   <link href="http://dafoster.net/articles/2010/09/17/comparing-writing-utensils/"/>
   <updated>2010-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://dafoster.net/articles/2010/09/17/comparing-writing-utensils</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My experience using various kinds of writing utensils in school&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;gt; = &amp;ldquo;is better than&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why Pens &gt; Pencils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t smudge ∴ Archive well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Force you to think about what you are writing

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes are more costly, since you cannot simply use an eraser on pen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have brighter contrast ∴ Easier to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Why Mechanical Pencils &gt; Traditional Pencils&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t need to be sharpened ∴

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No sawdust to clean up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No special sharpener hardware needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lifetime is not limited to a certain number of sharpenings

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lifetime only limited to when the m-pencil is lost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seem to resist smearing in the short term

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(but pens still win in the long term)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Why Writing Utensils &gt; Computer Keyboards [for creative projects]&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Force you to think about what you are writing

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It takes a long time (comparatively) to write individual words,
which gives you time to think about what you are writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes are more costly, since you cannot just delete words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Force you to think about the structure of what you are writing

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes are more costly, since you cannot just cut and paste sections
which are poorly laid out in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No mental overhead

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using computers always incurs at least a small bit of mental overhead
that interferes with the creative process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic revision control (in the case of pen)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easier to strike through (rather than erase) rejected ideas with
pen, so these ideas are preserved for future analysis, which sometimes
comes in handy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Why Computer Keyboards &gt; Writing Utensils [for non-creative projects]&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typing speed is much higher

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gets even better if you use typing expansion software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gets even better if you use dictation software [for prose]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gets even better if you use a stenotype machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyperlinks are easy to create and maintain

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is especially powerful when writing reference documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Comparing iPod Touch (2nd Gen) to iPhone 3GS</title>
   <link href="http://dafoster.net/articles/2010/09/17/comparing-ipod-touch-2nd-gen-iphone-3gs/"/>
   <updated>2010-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://dafoster.net/articles/2010/09/17/comparing-ipod-touch-2nd-gen-iphone-3gs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently upgraded from an iPod Touch to an iPhone 3GS. I hate contracts, so I
bought the 3GS off-contract from a seller on Craigslist. (And I timed my
purchase to coincide with the release of the iPhone 4, so lots of people were
dumping their own 3GS devices.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am routinely in WiFi hotspots: at home, enroute to work, and at work, so I
usually put the iPhone 3GS in &amp;ldquo;Airplane Mode&amp;rdquo;, where the wireless radios are
disabled, to conserve battery life. Therefore I effectively use my iPhone like
a better iPod Touch most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From purely a specification point of view, the differences are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;thead style=&quot;background-color:#e0e0e0;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
                &amp;nbsp;&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
                iPod Touch (2nd Gen)&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
                iPhone 3GS (3rd Gen)&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                internet access&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                only in WiFi hotspots&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                universal (except subway)*&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                geolocation&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                WiFi triangulation only, via SkyHook&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                GPS-enabled (very accurate)&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                external speaker quality&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                -&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                surprisingly better&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                CPU / responsiveness&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                -&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                much faster&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                battery life&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                - (approx 3 days)&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                less (approx 2 days)&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                vibrate capability&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                no&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                yes&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                built-in microphone&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                no&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                yes&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                heft&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                lighter and thinner&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                -&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                headphone jack location&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                bottom-right&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                top-left&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In practical terms, this translates to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;I never get completely lost*&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The combination of GPS plus internet everywhere means that I always know
where I am on the map.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can also get instant directions from my current location to an
arbitrary destination. I usually take public transit, but this works with
cars as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The iPhone is a better boombox&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use both devices as portable external sound systems while I work.
The better speaker quality of the iPhone is nice to have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The iPhone user interface is more responsive&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;thanks to the better CPU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The iPhone needs to be recharged slightly more often&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;thanks to the shorter battery life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I never miss calendar reminders anymore&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar reminders (including work meeting reminders) are not only
audible on the iPhone but also produce a noticeable vibration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I can use Shazam to identify random music I hear&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;thanks to the built-in microphone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Update:&lt;/strong&gt; This actually doesn&amp;rsquo;t work very well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I can make phone calls if I really want to&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The microphone makes it feasable. Not just for normal calls, but VoIP
internet calls as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a phone plan, you can make the normal calls as well.*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;* Requires phone plan, with associated subscription costs.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The uneasy marriage with AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate expensive monthly fees. Here in the USA, the only officially
supported carrier is AT&amp;amp;T, which charges at least $70/month. I don&amp;rsquo;t even use
the voice plan, so I&amp;rsquo;m being overcharged rather significantly at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T-Mobile is another option for those willing to unlock their iPhones. They
have less expensive plans, to the tune of $40/month, which I&amp;rsquo;m much in favor
of. I intend to unlock my iPhone when I get some spare time in the next month
or so. After all, it&amp;rsquo;s costing me $30/month to delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Update:&lt;/strong&gt; T-Mobile is rumored to be carrying the iPhone sometime in
2013. I just hope it isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;too little, too late.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Update:&lt;/strong&gt; I am still using the same iPhone 3GS today.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>